oh now it's working
hello
[Music]
[Applause]
that's what it all used to be before
what
[Music]
tell me to get it to just stop there's
no one here we didn't even code I don't
know I think we're just gonna listen to
emo music for hours I think we're doing
today
now we did you rebel today oh yeah okay
now get there I see yeah
no not playing anymore we'll get we'll
get the coding in a minute no all right
fine we'll stop doing that's why I know
I I know you viewers don't want this I
know I know twitches now if we get a
hundred viewers I'll play you a brand
new rap song I wrote a rap song I wrote
last week I don't think it's actually
worth releasing on soundcloud it's not
that high quality but um yeah if we get
if we get a hundred people I'll play it
all right let's make slam fast so where
were we
wow it's been a while guys oh god I had
a date Thursday night so I got home late
Friday and I didn't stream Friday and
I'm very sorry and then yesterday was
probably not you have an issue Oh Oh
stupid issues let's see what issues we
got I probably don't care about it
cannot work with tests Fryeburg yeah I
know man
probably she sucks last that's shitty
slam who wrote that shitty slam at least
someone else got it running that's
exciting okay yeah we should fix that
now we'll see if we got 100 maybe we'll
play a rap song um but now where are we
here we go
profile with flames search by projection
less stupid
don't add points to the optimum
aggression drive for pose at least I can
do that one that one's easy
could I fit in my closet it has to be
has a organic hundred organic that's
right like the guy who runs the rap
battles you know I'm talking about yeah
bro you guys ever watched battle rap no
like if you've never seen like battle
rap I don't know what's good brawling if
you've never seen this kind of man
super legit where's your glad to get an
armor get your heart of Spartacus sir I
am Sparta come on dog
if you guys have never seen Ballarat
what I accept a PRF for Windows support
if it's easy to maintain yeah okay so
first thing we're gonna change is we're
gonna improve the optimizer for hos stop
please I wanna go home a zoomed a zoom
down a little is that okay can you still
say they're friends de Graaff add points
wait so I'm already doing that
let's just pass verbose into that we
were actually doing here 45 edges okay
that's nice you're not bad
never mind already doing this
okay well it's really not optimizing it
much ever I'm just kind of shady I look
at the chives it stays the same
hmm that's interesting
winding wall frames even if they're not
local tribes oh yes I am
well we can certainly change that so if
we fix points their local frames if fix
points
how did that break who's got unlocked
still not optimizing for show local
fairs are fixed point out self-taught
frames and we should suck some weed
today I think we should from I'm not
really feeling this Red Bull I kind of
want coffee I kind of want Starbucks but
I can't bring you bros to Starbucks so
I'll have to go downstairs and settle
for closeted coffee but yeah I think I
think we were thoughtful weed today I
think so I think Sunday that's what we
do let's get blazed brah
but let's figure out where we are first
okay so I don't know why this doesn't
optimize it all some of those edges just
total garbage we can't optimize them six
points I'll sell my frames like that's
right we don't really need this
well it's not really optimizing and
those are pretty high errors actually
okay also why is this that and this that
that doesn't make sense crazy is not
working I mess something up
the FFF is not not an estimated playback
it goes crazy now okay let's figure out
what I got stop well
hmm now I'm fixing the positions of the
points so that should be okay you know
what let's just refactor this to do this
[Music]
how much do i smoke depends I'm coding
don't smoke that much guys in California
it's just legal bros not smoke
cigarettes so now I smoke spliffs it
smells pretty good but I spoken this a
lot
some sour tangi I bought this off a
friend you got it up in Eureka it smells
pretty good
no no though some sour tangi might be
check it out guys I'm not feeling that
I'm feeling this
oh it's XJ 13 there we go yeah there's
my smoke last time um see what else I
don't know my friend hold on folks the
Tevas cheerio gxj filling the next j13
yeah just weed I don't know you said no
more drugs I was younger I don't want to
do drugs that much anymore just weed
back to my office I was
on the grinder grind it out how often I
smoke at 18 oh really start smoking but
I lived in LA I would smoke weed every
day
now I smoke fake once or twice a week
I want to new I want to new what are
those things called I might have one I
found gross screams we got a USBC the
USBA that's probably work
you know I love this piece man oh man
look at look at that screen it's just
like torn to shreds in there yeah
this isn't really the best to us thank
you I like this sir
you know look look look at that look at
that screen
the bottom of my bowl
whatever we're not no it's clear let's
clear back all right so there's a bit of
guitar at the bottom of that yeah
brand-new gold screen I remember a
friend and I ran to the store to get
this loud smoke reading twitch they
get me call the twitch place on me
I don't think this
this is I can't I can't smoke all this
let's bolt this bowl see there's a thing
else like this bowl will last like at
least to smoking sessions oh nice good
but now honestly smoking weed with way
more Claude it was illegal now it's lost
cool you don't buy it is we bad for tell
Thea body I mean dude like it's like
drinking man if you're gonna drink like
my needs less Matthew the drinking
problem
healthy for you know what's supposed to
are healthy thing people do they don't
think
well that's a clean hit bros I love that
new screen none of that tar get it out
can we change the world I don't know
kids don't do drugs no no ma'am don't do
drugs to get up right
I think that's generally a thing like
some people talk about like all to a
drugs man so up with don't do
drugs for that you can idiot no but I'm
a big fan of drugs okay so where was I
why don't we write this very well no bit
want to say is this graph frame so
you're gonna complain about like that's
not a house and that's not a hashable
object baba wawa yeah probably
segmentation fault 11 ok well that's
another way of complaining what I know
there's always broken no it's not how
many lines of code early onset
well I've never had slot can't take that
home
Oh does it count as everything no we
only want 460 hmm well so I can't do
that anymore
see the problem this this this doesn't
work anymore this cover this verts never
none
hmm self-taught points equals new points
well you know I should sum up iterating
over self-taught points anymore can you
say here our self dot points what is it
how do I remove an element from a Python
all right remove the elements first
occurred in the list new points crap
your points is not defined see your
pro-white a break right
I really is this like a new regression
though that's what I don't want to
understand
when I'm reading opposed optimizer every
time that could be the problem
yeah we want to do that and support it
tight or what no it's still broken all
my essential matrices like that's weird
get initial positions from fundamental
matrix is that wrong now but I like
change something to make that wrong
don't put it this way
none of those changes introduced
[Music]
good bro now I see look the first two
were messed up so this has to be some
problem with the essential matrix that
was historically pretty reliable okay
yeah it's messing up that's actually
been happening for a while probably need
to invert it I'm just not
I just don't think that's right
okay it's like scary if that doesn't
really well it looks like my initializer
is just completely maybe the
bigger problem is just like RT is
garbage
yeah like every time it's saying to go
more that way this doesn't even look
like it's in the right the rotational
frame this one makes sense right okay so
this translation is coming from a coach
from the Central Asians that doesn't
make sense
that's that Wow
okay so that's what it's estimated this
is my essential matrix estimate as total
garbage I forget exactly what math is is
actually on the whole length of the
script earth lengths of matches length
of it in wire some live in wires well
maybe in Liars is just crap she's like
they got a completely different answer
well I get a different answer every time
that's even worse a lengthened liars is
short well that's just filtering out
ones that don't have work is this
how many more I mean it's a magic
threshold bad this isn't repeatable well
now it is my residual is just bad see if
it still messes up
Wow okay it's missing I've even worse
that's pretty good it's saying that it's
moving like this is total garbage
don't ask questions about like oh how
can I learn to code or what should I use
to code there's stupid questions
alright well this is great
tastes like correct myself I'm serious
Oh zip object
you Python three correct okay this
just given me a different answer every
time I swear this used to be better my
residual point isn't good just accepting
well now it's repeatably wrong which is
kind of more interesting it's amazing
actually how different these numbers are
every time fundamental to our T model
dot perhaps
I just didn't put in a pulse that way it
works
so what's taking so long with my stupid
a special matrix filter oh it's on
you're very good that's slow yeah so
this just is like this is the try
anything for the optimizer try anything
for the first one approach
works how it's moving that one shouldn't
be allowed to
I don't know how it moved that okay well
so it turns out that that's doing less
than nothing I mean that's concerning on
one level
yeah they do this Center and normalize
point to as much or how I feel
about
okay
[Music]
well no okay so you're gonna see the
problem with you with the initial
estimate right we don't really have a
good image after that it's good this
actually used to be okay before I even
could pose optimization and before I
even do the kinematic model huh that's
interesting it doesn't even matter where
I put them and it's fast
it's relying heavily on the velocity
model at last no wait I disabled the
velocity model
okay I mean this says something about
like whether the ShipWorks are hot which
is like not really
let's make telecommute that way
look at that like kind of fixes them
first off how amazing is that speed
let me optimize a little bit beause it
was true such thing would benefit from
more iterations
so you can literally put anything in for
the initial estimate of clothes you can
put in total garbage
and it gives you something except that
one the one over there all right no hos
optimization back
it's even higher quality sometimes does
that romance
it looks good once we put in pose
optimization
it is concerning to me that that just
doesn't work let's just do this the hell
is that
it's the Samsun distance here and it's
the actual interesting thing
this thing I wanted to do this Center in
normalize point residuals
it calls the same set up and straight
matrix I don't actually give a I
don't want someone here to talk to so
I'm not talking to myself well okay it's
amazing that fundamental matrices don't
seem to work at all really now but I
swear it used to I swear it used to what
change
I swear this used to work
moving that way is that what it looks
like why is the fundamental matrix doing
this and so that's with only fundamental
matrices may be used to only work on
like Ohio and this is what we
initially had no it doesn't work on Ohio
I find alright let's just implement this
class let's try with our own variant
that's why that was stupid mags
setup constraint very tricks sad ass
why don't you do that oh so that gets
the matrix so there's actually a second
constraint I can force because this is
an essential matrix basically this
[Music]
and now we also need the residual
function
that's matrix is not the fight
interesting
thank you a normalised point does this
do okay so I don't make sure it's gonna
just say like best no I can't
no nice points oh just don't even need
that that's better
like at least now it's ping pong in
between two reasonable solutions you say
well that's actually pretty good now so
okay this problem that this is a known
problem we don't know which is the
correct yeah okay you can't know whether
you're going like this or like this from
the fundamental matrix but that's much
better at least yeah I kind of think
they're like subtractor thing doesn't
work
let's make the assumption that it's
always moving
well the norm is always one but what do
we really want now yeah sounds pretty
good well how about you know what okay
so it's all about this way yeah cool so
it's doing that only with fundamental
matrices now that looks much better
I don't know what the bug was with the
other one
all right so that's without an optimizer
oh that's pretty good however why is it
filtering a lot that's good they're
doing a thousand trial also there's a
lots just as good with a hundred looks a
lot faster algorithm it's not bad now we
have a working essential matrix again oh
we actually don't know if that's let's
let's try it on the irritation one and
see if my rotations are reversed because
that might actually be universe knows
good
yeah so you see what it's doing the
essential matrix always has to have a
magnitude of translation of 100 so
technically this should be like an se
something qua interesting okay well
those tabs little taps no that was close
I want to miss all the optimization
know why it goes crazy like that isn't
problem
I don't know why I want to get to
hashman issues it's still rotating
stupid velocity model yeah we're not
here to talk about some very cars like
what why why do you think we are
that's interesting about a test is fail
sorry I said I'd be profiling today we
haven't done any profile you've just
done improved please no yes cool alright
that's back to looking pretty good
little bumps there like that's not good
let's just say a custom I'm not gonna
call it my own right I did copy it psych
it
five hundred million dollars guys what
the hell I do with five hundred million
dollars
can't deploy capital like that that's
the real scam of those icos you know
they don't realize like capital is not
always a food could be a burden right
how are you gonna wait 1 million how how
are you going to deploy 4 billion
dollars to improve euros you don't you
can't even scam with that should we do
live streaming crypto scams one of these
days
sometime I scam crypto there's so many
great scams and crypto blockchain block
chains okay well so turn off this
optimize are so powerful that even no
matter how crappy the rest of my slam is
it kind of works so I mean that's kind
of good but kind of bad because it's
masking other bugs okay so first off
let's get you rid of my kinematic model
because that's breaking things
like this was breaking our pie but okay
so you see like when the essential
matrix runs like it goes like that
I might pose optimizing okay why isn't
the pose optimizer fixing that that's
what I understand
kolmad is almost pure rotation so I'm
not really sure what they expect but
also like it shouldn't be doing that
Wow
okay so first of all these points are
total garbage because it's pure
translation
I hate that the optimizer does that was
my local frame window that's smaller
something
we've got crappy one what happens when I
put in the ground truth the scaling is
just stupid you know what I have a good
way to actually scale my country's stead
of adding scale program will multiply it
by one
it's becoming crappy so I left in some
optimism get a good crack doing the same
thing that bugs you don't rap about
blockchain okay guys
being nerd he's not cool don't be a nerd
all right I don't know who told you it
was they lied to you all right they like
you about a lot of don't be a nerd
it's not cool
okay well the optimizer is not and
that's all garbage should it really be
such garbage I mean I don't know these
are the ground truth poses
it's very concerning how would I run the
optimizer it changes things well we're
gonna be back to that shitty bugged
ready for this shitty bug you set set
fixed equal to true on all the frames
that just crashes watch yeah
highest-quality
what
yeah and now it's like doing that huh
okay I told you to fix all the frames
and I think it's just massively moving
the points or no it's just lying to me
I'm moving the frames set fixed out not
looks good
what's the error
let's run the verbose optimizer
okay there's some bugs here because I
don't understand like where there's any
error this is ground truth poses this
should have extremely low error and any
points that do have error should be
reported to the police immediately for
repointing
no no don't rap about nerdy being
nerd is not cool at the risk of quoting
Sam Biddle bring back bullying this
Apple yeah that guy exists hey so I
don't understand what let's let's work
out why with ground truth poses we're
getting a call that you guys are gonna
swap me man
that work in San Francisco I would hope
that if there's any city that's smart
enough okay so where are all these
errors that that's a great question
don't you think because TV like these
are the ground truth poses spit four
bars real quick I Drive big sick
whips brah you're right I see that you
run ball with bra oh and then like ride
up real quick you ain't gonna do
nah brah ha ha nah there you go some
rhymes hey my errors really high look
look I hear is bro there is more I need
me that
[Music]
all right um well some ways it's low
first of all that's us another that's
another pose optimizers off
turn optivisor off
don't think there's bugs anymore is my
ground treat slaughter right
let's disable search back projection
that's what's slop
that's how you get if you don't search
by projection you just get a lot of
points alright goes that way
comes back that way don't you wish it
was this fast IRL we can make search by
projection a lot faster
not change in the world not doing
doing things overrated kids stay home
smoke weed everyone always wants you to
do something I would always want you to
make something yourself don't do that
that's dumb
cuz it reads Bukowski sueda love life
it looks pretty good
to the points are all garbage like these
outliers but only I don't really
understand like all that noise do I have
other bugs I have to
oh okay so it actually looks like that
it's not pure rotation that's a lot
closer to pure rotation wait that's not
right what's that right there just have
a bad angle on it
that's right
and I guess that's right I just sort of
had an angle on it
cool
so this is the ground truth guys you're
better debugger yeah yeah yeah oh dude
dude dude that's a line man is that line
for the movie
we're not here to save the
manatees Bros we're here to get rich and
get the out
I like that line dude like I could see
that line in a heist movie I would watch
that
oh hey this IKEA movie oh cool I'm gonna
watch that okay now we add it back in
search by projection every point should
be a search by projection point this is
so low quality
you know what I'll Preiser every time
maybe it's better now but all the points
are like wiggling and look the errors
are crazy high still okay
that's that's the great mystery that
needs to be solved why are the errors
high to move all the points right fix
points is false that's not known I said
well why why is the error so high
okay GTO
[Music]
we get worse
that's high error which is which like
the pruners should be pruning these
things don't like crazy if I do that
okay well that second pulse us is even
better
well that definitely works like the
arsed and tiny
we're much more aggressively pruning
things now but actually it's possible
the era staying tiny because I'm
actually just deleting all the old
points which actually is probably more
likely
these errors are in like pixel space
though shadow maybe projector is really
low so why is this so much a hurry
you know we're not getting any more
copyright strikes you know I always log
in my videos are always D monetized do
you monetize you think if we watch
PewDiePie will copyright strike us yeah
maybe
okay so this this amount of error just
doesn't really make sense right look at
all that error it's terrible
set vertex vertex F dot ID you can do
those is more exciting you change this
to graph rating so that forget error
still getting large I don't understand
what this set marginalize means I think
worst lenders are never this I Wow it's
twitch slam look at that it's Twitter
I'm famous
Wow 68 stars not bad Bruce
we will watch the boiler-room quote
sorry I don't care copyrights are one
reason become filthy rich that's it
I'm not here to make friends we're not
saving the manatees here guys
what vacation time go teach their great
public school I gotta watch the school
all right so I got something to do today
is let him do it I'm watching that movie
that's what I'm doing after after after
robust Colonel set vertex at
the point and we had the edge fixed
false marginalize true sent information
oh this is actually a much cuter
encoding they don't have a stupid point
ID offset oh that's fair this was
written by smart people yeah I mean it's
not gonna fix the everything at all but
it's a much this cute do you guys see
what that did though 69 stars right I
mean we're not even up to as many stars
I got a mariner 64 game in like two and
a half hours brow yeah I think I think I
could get a four hour 120 that could be
a livestream
okay error still high error should be
low well okay so this is an interesting
question what is Kam baseline is that it
detect did nothing do you like plus 100
here oh my dad thankful don't do plus
100 there Bros you get side fault
let's play over there do I get seg fault
you get back so much seg fault Oh using
a different solver for me that's
interesting that nobody won't get Chobot
error anymore because I'm not using
chole bot okay this still has crazy high
error but it does seem like it might
crash last maybe
that looks visually very good why does
it have high error to make a new robust
kernel for everyone
get rid of the end what do I get
trap inside even with my new favorite
optimizer see sparse III way okay
era is still really high look at that
those errors try to czar errors right
okay six four point something for error
it's not
no I was check my phone gross okay
uninteresting okay public se3
quads oh it's an S III quat o unit image
projection is that
Oh zero we want zero maybe one zero oh
well the air is still high but I think
we do 1 zero
I think that does anything but look at
the air so high well fine so let's let
it optimize the poses again see we get
we get 70 pulse 11
I don't care doesn't move them that much
ok the arrow doesn't explode it that
whatever that's fixing is the solution
I think that looks like crap when I run
the optimizer and let it optimize the
pose we kind of see the bug what's nice
this is very nice visual debug so it
seems maybe like mike haeseong 525 320
240 so this it is it is 5.5 right my ass
all right let's try that
way more ok so 525 is probably pretty
close right bird why not all I get is
twitch slam okay that's the same
matrix effective way
point one texel dust and honor
it's not a k problem but yet when I let
the optimizer move the frames I get crap
yeah I've heard rumors to Freiburg is a
real place I don't know if I believe
them
see look look at that it shouldn't
have to do that
just keep the error lower but like it's
not right clearly okay when I don't let
it move the frames the error certainly
gets launched so there's a bug somewhere
let's be a set can adjust the double
baseline derivatives the rotation matrix
with respect to jacobians don't even
know about that well so that's
interesting do I need to do this
once it could turn e on there
this is the only thing I'm thinking to
be wrong I set the pose when I put it
back
rotation dot matrix there's no rotation
let's see if that's
better than say estimate
[Music]
hmm
I mean okay it's possible I'm like doing
something wrong it's possible like you
want to like apply the matrix on to the
translation or something the only thing
I'm thinking is that my pose estimate is
wrong so what if I say
mm-hm
okay that's wrong looks cool all right
and shares about the same error which is
weird
you don't think I'm thinking as if
they're representing pose like
differently for me somehow
let's just get rid of that
don't you need to do that all the girls
go crazy hi ever higher air so it wants
the Lynn Elgin what are the losses on
the rotation
now don't worry they were illegal for
the good of the people like that just
makes it seem wrong makes it seem like I
have like my pose wrong those points
there's like a question of which you
apply first
on apply the rotation
people like that doesn't matter for this
which means it could be wall
there's low
okay let's focus on why the error is
increasing
okay so that direction all the points
are positive all right well you lost
your edge it was over source right
what's the interesting Pichu MCH edge
project p2m say freedom I do all types I
want you to M save means vertex cap why
am I not using vertex cap when we're
using SBA can point to camera projection
monocular p2s
don't know any of that
hacked my computer bra see okay the only
thing that could be wrong is the
ordering of rotation and translation and
I'm not really sure how this stuff works
but what if I didn't use SBA cap what if
instead I use the vertex K I don't know
what SBA
I'm already using vertex can God SBA cab
is just the estimates the vertex pose
dot orientation pose dot position
I mean see like that's the thing right
what is position me
see how that matrix is going to apply
Teairra should not be this away I mean
okay wait we are increasing the number
of edges
well that looks beautiful look at how
beautiful that look sorry I don't want
that den slam get there we'll get there
first
I'm out of Red Bull come back in five
minutes coffee
we got coffee labeled coffee no way this
is a different problem or blemish using
the optimizer in a different way it
doesn't make that much sense posed on
orientation posed opposition it's an
example
pose here means transform points from
world coordinates to camera coordinates
okay I mean that's yeah that's like what
I'm doing it's fine it's not that okay
breakdown like where the errors are what
is the set marginalize do I take it out
if I crashes and crashes does all these
errors
they are creating a new robust tunnel
for each one and they're using a
different edge for check let's try that
one
that type rating
pick outliers randomly okay bad type ID
and why's that
okay
[Music]
come on I better add a bad type I do
they have the camera as a global thing
oh I like this okay this is kind of nice
it has the camera up here I like that
because we'll be able to add
optimization together oh wait the hats
well I think this actually might let us
optimize the camera - that's exciting
who's excited about that I know I red
bull is highly addictive gross
let's create the robots eternal chef
Donna Thomas only because they do it the
example how much dumber is done
because it's done with examples one too
many parentheses ok variable F reference
before assignment that's true it was a
little bad type ID well it's a parameter
I do because we're on setting parameter
ID which means that's for the camera so
that tells you how to use the camera
segmentation vault 11 aw it's my
favorite segmentation fault I love it so
informative when it does that or tells
me so much about what went wrong is the
problem in the pudding back
let's be real number one time the arrow
goes from large to models are and of
that there are problems in their putting
back
that dress throws all the points of life
geeky cuz they have bugs
doing that one of their own hidden
that's interesting
and there's still errors but they're I
think they're lower
not that much lower yeah well we think
guys is that what better or worse I
switched the other optimizer the other
optimizer doesn't take poses and inverse
for that reason alone I kind of liked it
right and hos is not defined what
rewards and rest we do an inverse when
we do projection no we don't
okay there's still high errors but
they're different
it's an average of three error per hench
does that seem reasonable soft wiser
seems slower okay well we had the other
one working - I don't know I don't know
which one's better
sigh to UVO happiness
oh I don't know you want the old one or
do we want this one why this probably
old one don't one looks newer let me set
each camera separately
the heirs are noticeably higher with the
same to show exactly the same oh my god
why are they so high I don't understand
that should be throwing out all things
that have point that are above
yeah so this is just that we can use
either one I'm not sure which is better
yet
there are we had ten minutes ago guys
Wow look at that so fun I cool so this
is the alternative optimizer let's like
we let it optimize frames
it actually looks literally at now able
to get along
so maybe slower let's just look so doing
this thing every time
why am I getting those bumps
why does that look like crap the errors
are not that high
they're staying at like 13,000 they're
growing slightly
still there's less errors than edges
when I let it off to miss frames why
don't run it out to my friends let's see
if this happens off with the other
optimizer let's first see if I didn't
break that are optimized just seem
crappy or do you think
but yet I hated getting lower hours
these bumps I think that's not really in
the data set as far as I know
you just have some garbage points like
my rejection to get back okay that one
doesn't agree better I'll clear this up
so you can actually commit this
sometimes let's run it without that key
error okay I broke -
how did I write that ah because it adds
all the frames that's interesting oops
so we only had the edges the frames
actually in the graph now we didn't pose
opt again
it's a nice like a map
[Music]
so now we just we're both optimizers oh
and I disabled to came out oh it was
shitty
look at our shitty that box it can't be
what it really is
why does it always like jerk it forward
like that
change the worlds of scam they'll do it
if you're thinking about it should
reconsider what you're doing with your
life and realize that it's a lot easier
to change yourself than it is to change
the world
garbage but this is also with the higher
pruning threshold to change that
do that jumped fix that but still
why does it jump back if we can answer
that question
well that actually jumps back
why not keeping some stayed around
accidentally or something this friend
gets called again it's called with the
map there's one map optimized actually
changes it know you want to spy on
people guys to spy on all of us I'm
going to call that you guys don't
ask so Google does by exploits
absolutely okay so it seems like after
the optimizer runs it gives me a crappy
pulse which is weird
the new new pose after the optimizer
runs is crappy seems like it's like
doesn't want to move the current pose or
something you guys see what's going on
but it globally optimizes and that it
just like shoves the frame back there
I just jobs
big jump on that one it's not even pose
optimizing edge
and this is without a local window tel
just will actually move all of them the
optimizer decides that's the best see
just jumps back there I love this look
at that gap why does that happen
hmm
it moves them and then it just jumps
right back
well 50s and I helping anybody
we do only paint the map after we
display it sometimes we don't run that
optimizer the kinematic model is
disabled right now and f 2 dot pose will
actually change definitely right
it's still doing it
- jumping back look at the jumps
that's without you pose optimization
that's just using fundamental matrices B
dot F 2 dot oh yeah that right there
no
okay runs the optimizer that should be
huh
we're praying the universe of the post
yeah I'm from University that's fine
since the FS that's the transform from
there there there there I went backwards
there's backwards why did it do that
that's what I don't understand there
guys see it look goes forwards and then
it goes backwards I'm totally backwards
slicked down why did that happen
look at that you can see it better from
this side down right there right there
that's supposed to be after pose
optimization
I don't do pose optimization but one of
it was one of the RT matrices cared
know that look at that bad frame went
there that's wrong I didn't do it that
time it did the down there so putting in
the ground truth
and it's jumping down do it I don't put
in the ground truth just move them all
gently down
moving sideways cow
don't Optima still do that but you know
because if I don't laugh
but who wants to move that one down why
are those points such garbage I see you
but when you talk about
self-driving cars and , I don't respond
don't forget it moves it down why does
it think it's more down than it is
okay it does vaguely look to me like it
actually did move down
look at that
- both optimizers - it does it even more
so that's the first frame right after we
did a global bundle adjustment
that just set let's see the problem I
don't want to try another video like
that didn't move down that doesn't make
sense that matrix said it didn't move
down this matrix said it didn't move
down how did it move down
then my output here is that's down well
no that's all wrong access yeah look my
upper here is 62 does it make sense good
it didn't run the optimizer and the last
pose was this okay
something weirds going on here you guys
see what's up notice how this one is
point O 4 then we dotted with 0.05 which
is what should give me the pose here
wait - 48 we think about my corner
friend
so yeah wait how did that get minus 48
how did that get 60 - that's the bigger
question alright cuz this and this does
not 60 to make
how is that at all different from that
didn't even run another optimizer
there's no pose optimizer right oh we
have ground truth for the pose oh okay I
see what's going on it's using the
ground truth the OP okay sorry I'm being
dumb the optimizer is moving it away
from the ground truth Bob and then the
ground truth comes back and it's like oh
it's actually there right I'm not using
like the differences from the ground
truth I'm using the ground truth it's
sell okay well that explains the mystery
at least okay electricity PPS mysteries
over that line that was pretty sick all
right so now we're just left with the
question of why the optimizer makes the
frames go there I mean that's a much
more banal question that seems less like
a bug and more like by
I mean you know those things that we
can't really fix see that looks better
but now the points look crappier
all these crappy points but these can't
have good
these can't have good losses
relax these ones that are like zero and
wanna like okay well I think that is
their depth but I can't tell too much
about them
you know we're gonna pause after you're
in adoption so this is what the
optimizer outputs yeah like these guys
should be pruned at that point where's
that point there that should be proved
called 20 points and call way more
points that only left in crap
yeah we delete it if the error is large
that's good
so the problem like these others has
something to do with that family just
some of the really crappy ones notice
how some of the points I didn't move
those ones didn't move in a garbage
I don't know why the pruna didn't get
those look at those garbage
okay I'm just I'm just doing the
purchase a straight-up normal projection
so after I put the frame pose back so
that's right all the ones that don't
move it just garbage okay they might
only exist in two frames and somehow
like the two frames have their match
somewhere reasonable they will go away
eventually maybe okay it does remove
them eventually if they're not seen in
multiple frames so those are just
outliers in an optimization
these are the estimated depth of the
points some of them are really huge
we should filter those out or asked some
- who's greater than say a thousand I'm
stamping within a thousand away well
that's not really right we're gonna do
it for now but
it's not helping with anything okay
we're more aggressively prune on
reprojection these points are all still
in garbage garbage
how's that trash points Tanner out
alright let's get more aggressive
it does look like most of the trash
vanishes
trash just shows up look at all that
well but there's not much parallax there
is the problem so that's actual filter
we can do better all these new points
that aren't found they're not found
search by projection may be more lenient
on my search by projections or my search
by projections
that looks better
yeah more leniency on the searchbar
projections
getting all of that crap though well
that can be done by such by projection
really it's like speckle speckle
those points get found with search by
projection they shouldn't be used
anywhere if they shouldn't be out of the
map ever well it's not really true yeah
considered the trade opportunity that
after search by projection these matches
back get rid of the speckle
we didn't do any profiling I'm sorry
spackle man holy
garbage like Oh a garbage has showed up
garbage man Bronx Zoo quality
your box is pretty much is it true
the speckle it's staying in the map
somehow
I guess it just finds it in all the
frames and like that's okay hmm speckle
it's terrible
well it's better when I let the Abdul
observations of the point is already
observed in the previous frame okay
that's fine
you don't judge they're not aggressive
this one do this and that's a less
aggressive filter hoops no points anyone
I think those are the checks that orb
slam is doing that are pretty good but I
don't have right now this is also wrong
I shouldn't do this this is garbage
I wanna see if any descriptors I want to
find the best
oh no it's just a now that's fine
so like the problem with this is this
can actually add multiple observations
of the same point as far as I can tell
all right
well not not at the same point but
because that break is just breaking or
oh that's a bug yeah I see the problem
so first we can just say be desk so but
the problem is that we can actually
match it with multiple things next
observation all right well that's at
least gonna fix it to what it was before
cuz that's a vodka that might have been
why was crashing - we should add a
check for that me okay
so effectively what this is is
okay the the bug was that multiple
points were being observed multiple
times in the same frame this is just
going to work Randy that was with the
bug less like the structure the graph
was weird
oh my assertion fails that's interesting
object of type math has no leg yeah it's
being added multiple sources in afraid
oh god okay so the question how that's
happening no we gotta with sierpinski a
point can't be observed multiple times
in French so as the problem in search by
projection I'm gonna route and find out
yes it is so this still has the same
bomb okay so you don't actually need
that check but
yeah okay so for the points for each
point
yeah okay you see it can just be added
multiple times that should fix that
though if F points mi DX is not alright
but my search by projection has who
can find bug and win $1 $1 find the bug
win $1 if I had then no ID then mo you
but I don't cuz it's a Facebook product
or something so you guys have a Facebook
that Oh Facebook
yeah errors are cut it's interesting
ok so this is what happens when you
don't do search my projection we don't
really need it it's just bugged now I
have an Instagram bro I got I'm on insta
idea idea I'm Instagram models that's
what you're doing Instagram and invite
them to my palace in Dubai tag sponsor
I so this is what happens that we don't
do search better projection we won't say
for a projection now we just don't want
broken search by projection so let's see
what's broken about it
okay so first project all the map points
into current so that's not really right
but whatever only two points that fit
that's good
don't post on my insta brows you don't
follow my secret in stuff psyche I don't
have a secret in stuff you got time that
I don't sorry okay Katie query ballpoint
so for each one we get all the points
nearby in frame if the point is
unmatched then we add the observation
breakout now I don't get it that should
actually be okay
Frane points of ID x equals self
so it actually shouldn't be able to add
the observation twice I don't get it
alright is also aggressive that doesn't
do it anymore it just takes longer okay
well if you're gonna see a product make
an appetizer you can change it to later
a cert length of set IDs okay so the
indexes
so it's not that I'm sure we listen to
music listen to music now so we're
adding the observation to f1 multiple
times that's what's happening so for a
given point but if we have the
observation should break
should break out of that loop and we
only get a write over the points once
when one says p dot or just one factor
that's clear I'm gonna fix that um
how is that happening
f1 kt query ball points that gives us
indices into the frame throw assert is
good
you should people should have sir if
unmatched the distance
alright so the problem is actually that
a point is being added multiple times to
a frame the same point
which I really don't understand because
we only run this once
Raja's by
it's just a wave it doesn't matter what
back to return every point you shouldn't
do anything bad I just said that in that
observation ha what's good so now we can
remove that sanity check from the actus
guys stupid
so frame not itself alright so we are
literally adding same thing twice
No so it doesn't make that much sense
cuz I've never seen
at that point somehow already has an
observation in that frame understand
explicit check for it
oh I mean yeah you know I just there
let me get it up there and I have it
down there I mean there's nothing that
stops it point unmatched
and this point doesn't already have a
match in the for me let's yeah I don't
really understand why this is happening
there's nothing useful for like
desk times it was good for neural
networks and that's pretty much it I
mean you can try to right bundle just my
tensor flow but don't do it'll work well
I think actually have tried if you check
my gist's okay alright alright so what's
the problem the point f1 point sub mi DX
already has a match in the frame f1
yet it's just not to mig access to some
other point so although that point may
not have a map oh god I don't understand
this self assert that the point is not
matched and assert that the frame does
not already have a link to this point
how could a frame have a link to this
point frame dot points uh by DX if I D X
is something else are you paper there's
a point here's a point it's the same
point just added it multiple times to
the frame somehow
don't want to be so dumb about this I
don't know why this is so hard to think
about points of MIG axes yeah okay we'll
just put it up here if if F 1 in p dot
frames continue already okay fix us up
is there a chance that that even fixes
the segfault nope it does not be sampled
go get some mati that's kind of what I'm
talking about right
we've already matched this map point to
this frame I mean it's a map point yeah
right so of course it can already be
match to this frame
if you have to reopen and you close that
and try it again
there we go
all right now this is not letting it
optimize the frame its running off the
light the frame again okay it's still a
total piece of oh that's great oh
look it's still jumping back I love it
oh thank you thank you I putting all
that effort I find a bug and it gives me
nothing thank you
alright guys thanks for watching today's
stream sorry we didn't get more
accomplished yeah down in ten it's lunch
time
time to eat lunch just and this better
it happens up here doesn't happen here
it happens when it's found in both the
new observations did I write two limes
no it's lunchtime
that's junk automatic models junk let's
just make sure it still kind of works
pretty good don't know why it's jumping
all over the place like that we will get
to that next time get the commit though
great descriptive name to do stream this
afternoon uh maybe he'll say no I'm
gonna go I'm go I'm gonna work I go into
work on the weekend you know we got
things to do
we like when people come into work on
the weekends all right whoa geez